<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<ead xmlns="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9"
     xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
     xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
     xsi:schemaLocation="urn:isbn:1-931666-22-9 http://www.loc.gov/ead/ead.xsd">
   <eadheader countryencoding="iso3166-1"
              dateencoding="iso8601"
              findaidstatus="completed"
              langencoding="iso639-2b"
              repositoryencoding="iso15511">
      <eadid>US::CMalG::IA10030</eadid>
      <filedesc>
         <titlestmt>
            <titleproper type="filing">J. Paul Getty Trust, Getty Oral History Program Interviews Overseen/Conducted by University of California, Berkeley, 2015-ongoing</titleproper>
            <titleproper>Finding Aid for the Getty Oral History Program Interviews Overseen/Conducted by  University of California, Berkeley, 2015-ongoing, J. Paul Getty Trust <num>IA10030</num>
            </titleproper>
            <author>Nancy Enneking</author>
         </titlestmt>
         <publicationstmt>
            <publisher>Institutional Records and Archives</publisher>
            <p>
               <date>2017</date>
            </p>
            <address>
               <addressline>1200 Getty Center Drive, Suite 1100</addressline>
               <addressline>Los Angeles 90049-1688</addressline>
               <addressline>Business Number: (310) 440-7390</addressline>
               <addressline>reference@getty.edu</addressline>
               <addressline>URL: <extptr xlink:href="http://www.getty.edu/research/special_collections/institutional_archives/"
                          xlink:show="new"
                          xlink:title="http://www.getty.edu/research/special_collections/institutional_archives/"
                          xlink:type="simple"/>
               </addressline>
            </address>
         </publicationstmt>
      </filedesc>
      <profiledesc>
         <creation>This finding aid was produced using ArchivesSpace on <date>2023-11-07 16:59:32 -0800</date>.</creation>
         <langusage>Description is in English.</langusage>
         <descrules>Describing Archives: A Content Standard</descrules>
      </profiledesc>
   </eadheader>
   <archdesc level="collection">
      <did>
         <repository>
            <corpname>Institutional Records and Archives</corpname>
         </repository>
         <unittitle>Getty Oral History Program interviews, overseen/conducted by University of California, Berkeley,</unittitle>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n50022260" role="ive" source="naf">Ruscha, Edward</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n2005055663"
                      role="ivr"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">Meeker, Martin</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <corpname authfilenumber="n85059259" role="cre" source="naf">J. Paul Getty Trust</corpname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="oca04138288 " role="ive" source="naf">Agnew, Neville,, 1938-</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="no97058431" role="ive" source="naf">Druzik, James R.</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n50037672" role="ive" source="naf">Irwin, Robert, 1928-</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="no2016052848" role="ive" source="naf">Terrill, Joey, 1955-</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="no2007101658"
                      role="ive"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">Stoner, Joyce Hill</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n92072729" role="ive" rules="aacr" source="naf">Considine, Brian B.</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n83210739" role="ive" source="naf">Kren, Thomas, 1950-</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n86866186" role="ive" rules="aacr" source="naf">Hamma, Kenneth</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname role="ive" rules="aacr">Price, Merritt</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="nb2004303140"
                      role="ive"
                      rules="aacr"
                      source="naf">Schilling, Michael R.</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n2011080945" role="ive" source="naf">Szafran, Yvonne</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname role="ive" rules="rda" source="local">Siart, William (Bill)</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname role="ive" rules="rda" source="local">Kozberg, Joanne Corday</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname role="ive" rules="rda" source="local">Taylor, Peter J.</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n88207488" role="ive" source="naf">Podany, Jerry</persname>
         </origination>
         <origination label="Creator">
            <persname authfilenumber="n84020486" role="ive" source="naf">Gaehtgens, Thomas W., 1940-</persname>
         </origination>
         <unitid>IA10030</unitid>
         <physdesc altrender="part">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">252 GB</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <physdesc altrender="whole">
            <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">2.4 Linear Feet</extent>
            <extent altrender="carrier">(7 boxes)</extent>
         </physdesc>
         <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2015/2022" type="inclusive">2015-2022</unitdate>
         <abstract id="aspace_d19c2b7473e9ae1d9674d39751a173df">Records currently consist of printed transcripts and flash drives containing Word, PDF, MP3 and MP4, wav, and raw video files, dating 2015-2022, of the oral histories created as a part of the new 2015- Getty Oral History Program initiated by Trust President James Cuno and overseen/conducted by Martin Meeker, oral historian with The Oral History Center, Bancroft Library, University of California Berkeley.</abstract>
         <physloc id="aspace_3ef40460fc1a404d96e3821345453815">To access physical materials at the Getty, go to the <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest"
                    xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/10020/ALMA21182799970001551"
                    xlink:show="new">library catalog record</extref> for this collection and click "Request an Item."  Click here for <extref xlink:actuate="onRequest"
                    xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/10020/access"
                    xlink:show="new">general library access policy</extref>. See the Administrative Information section of this finding aid for access restrictions specific to the records described below.  Please note, some of the records may be stored off site; advanced notice is required for access to these materials.</physloc>
         <langmaterial>
            <language langcode="eng" scriptcode="Latn">English</language>
.    </langmaterial>
      </did>
      <bioghist id="aspace_28c3224f182a3876084cd6f244758cb2">
         <head>The Getty Oral History Program, 2015-ongoing</head>
         <p>The J. Paul Getty Trust has had a number of internal oral history initiatives throughout its brief history.  The projects have fallen into rough categories of Interviews Regarding the Study of Art History (1986, 1988, 1990), Interviews with Art  Historians (1991-2002) and Interviews of Significant Getty Trustees and Staff, organized by historical period and institutional role of interviewee (1999-2010).  The interviewers of the first two categories were Richard Candida-Smith and, to a lesser extent, Claire Lyons, while the interviewer of the third category was Eric Abrahamson.</p>
         <p>The Getty is a young institution of major consequence in its field, perceived by many to be among the leaders - and sometimes being the leader - in specific aspects of its field's work. Though informative, none of the earlier initiatives have fully expressed the Getty's exceptional nature or addressed the transformative quality of its leadership.   Additionally, many of the earlier interviews are closed for the life of the participant and therefore currently unavailable for research. The new 2015-ongoing initiative, proposed by President and CEO James Cuno, is intended to fill these gaps, producing publicly accessible interviews that discuss the Getty's extraordinary role in the world. Being a young institution, the Getty has access to all but the very first generation of its predecessors and colleagues, making this a timely project.  </p>
         <p>In this Getty Oral History Project, oral histories will fall into two broad categories.  The existing category "Interviews of Significant Getty Trustees and Staff'' will be continued, commencing with the departure of former President and CEO Barry Munitz in 2006, and using a thematic approach, e.g., "the resolution of the governance crisis in 2006-2007 (Attorney General investigation, Los Angeles (LA) Times articles, etc.)," "the negotiations with Italy and Greece over the return of antiquities," "the hiring of Jim Wood as President/CEO," "the response to the financial crisis," "Jim Wood's tenure as President/CEO," "the development of the individual Programs since 2006," and "reflections of the Trustees upon their departure," etc.  In addition, the existing categories "Interviews Regarding the Study of Art History" and "Interviews with Art Historians" will be combined and expanded to include conservators, conservation scientists, relevant arts philanthropists, and art museum directors and curators. The purpose of this category is to capture the current state of the field within which the Getty works and provide a context for understanding the developing role of the Getty within it.</p>
         <p>The Getty plans to work with Oral History Center (OHC) of the Bancroft Library at the University of California, Berkeley, to conduct thirty interviews annually, ten from Getty Staff and Trustees and twenty from leaders in its field, beginning with three interviews as a pilot project to assess quality and direction. Within the Getty, internal oversight of the project vests with a team comprised of the Getty's four Program Directors and Trust President, with the VP/COO/CFO, VP/General Counsel, VP Communications, and VP Development providing advice, as necessary.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <bioghist id="aspace_feaaef49c7356b2100698762ee26ba41">
         <head>The J. Paul Getty Trust</head>
         <p>The J. Paul Getty Trust is a cultural and philanthropic institution dedicated to the presentation, conservation, and interpretation of the world's artistic legacy. Through the collective and individual work of its constituent programs—the Getty Conservation Institute, the Getty Foundation, the J. Paul Getty Museum, and the Getty Research Institute—the Getty pursues its mission in Los Angeles and throughout the world, serving both the general interested public and a wide range of professional communities in order to promote a vital civil society through an understanding of the visual arts. </p>
         <p>The origins of the J. Paul Getty Trust date to 1953, when J. Paul Getty established the J. Paul Getty Museum as a California charitable trust to house his growing art collections. Originally a small, private institution located in Mr. Getty's ranch house near Malibu, the museum moved to the newly constructed Getty Villa in grounds adjacent to the ranch house in 1974. When most of Mr. Getty's personal estate passed to the trust in 1982, the trustees decided that, given the size of the endowment, it should make a contribution to the visual arts and humanities that would reach even beyond the museum. Out of this resolve grew an expanded commitment to the arts in the general areas of scholarship, conservation, and education. Harold M. Williams was the first president and CEO of the Trust, serving from 1981 through 1998.  Williams supervised the Trust's development of new programs, with the advice and recommendations of advisors such as Lani Duke and Nancy Englander.  The programs included the Center for the History of Arts and Humanities, Art History Information Institute, Conservation Institute, and Center for Education in the Arts, as well as smaller programs, such as the Museum Management Institute and the Program for Art on Film.  In 1983 the Trust's name was changed from the J. Paul Getty Museum to the J. Paul Getty Trust to reflect its broader scope, with the museum becoming an operating program of the Trust. As of 2010 the Trust supports and oversees four programs: the J. Paul Getty Museum, the Getty Foundation, the Getty Conservation Institute, and the Getty Research Institute. </p>
         <p>Due to expanded operations and limited space at the original J. Paul Getty Museum in Pacific Palisades (near Malibu), the various programs of the J. Paul Getty Trust were located at different sites throughout the Los Angeles basin during the 1980s and mid 1990s.  The Trust's vision was to bring together most of their programs at a single site.  A roughly 750-acre property in Brentwood (west Los Angeles) was purchased by the Trust in 1983 and the following year the architectural firm Richard Meier &amp; Partners was chosen to design the Getty Center, to house the Trust, its newly created programs, and an additional space for the Museum.  Currently, the J. Paul Getty Trust and Getty programs serve a varied audience from both locations: the Getty Center in Los Angeles and the Getty Villa near Malibu, California.  </p>  
      </bioghist>
      <bioghist id="aspace_82224a49c0010c54941d01e878402667">
         <head>The Oral History Center, Bancroft Library, University of California Berkeley</head>
         <p>Since 1954 the Oral History Center of the Bancroft Library, formerly the Regional Oral History Office, has been interviewing leading participants in or well-placed witnesses to major events in the development of Northern California, the West, and the nation. Oral history is a method of collecting historical information through recorded interviews between a narrator with firsthand knowledge of historically significant events and a well-informed interviewer, with the goal of preserving substantive additions to the historical record. The recording is transcribed, lightly edited for continuity and clarity, and reviewed by the interviewee. The corrected manuscript is bound with photographs and illustrative materials and placed in The Bancroft Library at the University of California, Berkeley, and in other research collections for scholarly use. Because it is primary material, oral history is not intended to present the final, verified, or complete narrative of events. It is a spoken account, offered by the interviewee in response to questioning, and as such it is reflective, partisan, deeply involved, and irreplaceable.</p>  
      </bioghist>
      <scopecontent id="aspace_1364215dad9415f416f3e61b53a5976c">
         <head>Scope and Contents</head>
         <p>Records currently consist of printed transcripts and flash drives containing Word, PDF, MP3 and MP4, wav, and raw video files, dating 2015-2022, of the oral histories created as a part of the new 2015- Getty Oral History Program initiated by Trust President James Cuno and conducted by Martin Meeker, oral historian with The Oral History Center (OHC), Bancroft Library, University of California Berkeley.  Interviews and video clips may be viewed under the <extref xlink:show="new"
                    xlink:actuate="onRequest"
                    xlink:href="http://www.lib.berkeley.edu/libraries/bancroft-library/oral-history-center/search-oral-histories">Getty Trust</extref> project on the Berkeley Oral History Center website.</p>

         <p>All interviews are recorded on high-quality digital video. Each interview is transcribed in its entirety. Draft transcripts are lightly edited by OHC staff and then provided to each interviewee for his/her review and approval. At this point, interviewees are  given the opportunity to edit, delete, and/or seal all or portions of their transcript (to the extent permissible under law) for a designated period of time as well. OHC staff then prepare a final transcript, which entails entering the interviewee's edits and preparing a discursive table of contents; if portions of a transcript have been sealed, OHC will prepare two transcripts: an expurgated version for immediate public release and an unexpurgated version that will be placed under seal until the designated release date. Interviewee-approved transcripts are then provided to the Getty to review prior to public release. The Getty has the right to determine if individual transcripts and accompanying audio/visual files (or portions thereof) should be sealed or otherwise put into limited public release (e.g. available only in research libraries) for a designated period time as well. No single transcript or accompanying audiovisual file will be published, deposited in an archive, or otherwise made available to the public until both the interviewee and the Getty provide formal approval. The goal of these measures is to create an environment in which interviewees feel secure in providing as candid and incisive interviews as possible and to protect any proprietary information that may be included in the interviews.</p>

      </scopecontent>
      <prefercite id="aspace_ff05fa29ee1c24fe791faa6978daa286">
         <head>Preferred Citation</head>
         <p>[Cite the item and series (as appropriate)], Getty Oral History Program 2015-ongoing, J. Paul Getty Trust in collaboration with the the Oral History Center, Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley.  Institutional Archives,  Research Library, Getty Research Institute, Finding aid no. IA10030.</p>
         <p>http://hdl.handle.net/10020/cifaia10030</p>  
      </prefercite>
      <accessrestrict id="aspace_f95a2961facc4a52a51f1c3c2299cbdb">
         <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
         <p>Unless transcripts have been sealed by the participant, the 2015-ongoing Getty Oral History Program Interviews are unrestricted and open to the public.</p>
         <p>The following types of records are permanently closed: records containing personal information, records that compromise security or operations, legal communications, legal work product, and records related to donors. The J. Paul Getty Trust reserves the right to restrict access to any records held by the Institutional Archives.</p>  
      </accessrestrict>
      <arrangement id="aspace_e9ebffe35ae65a90347616d567eebd13">
         <head>Arrangement</head>
         <p>Records are organized into two series: 
I. Interviews with the arts community, 2015-2019;
II. Interviews of significant Getty trustees and staff, 2016-2022.</p>  
      </arrangement>
      <altformavail id="aspace_a735508e9f41c86185b2f79862f20639">
         <head>Existence and Location of Copies</head>
         <p>In addition to being made available at their home at the Getty, approved interview transcripts along with selected approved video clips drawn from interviews will be posted to the OHC website and cataloged by The Bancroft Library, and listed in the MELVYL and OSKICAT catalogs. The OHC will work with the Getty to publicize the release of the interviews and to encourage the use of the materials by scholars, journalists, activists, and the public at large at a date agreeable to all parties.</p>  
      </altformavail>
      <acqinfo id="aspace_9b893f120505958d63b10bb0a25bf301">
         <head>Immediate Source of Acquisition</head>
         <p>The records in 2016.IA.34 were deposited with the Institutional Archives in March 2016 (additional clarifications and finalized sets were deposited in March 2017).
The records in 2017.IA.61 were deposited with the Institutional Archives in July 2017.
The transcripts in 2018.IA.76 were deposited with the Institutional Archives in December 2018 (digital files were not included at that time). 
Digital files and three transcripts were accessioned in December of 2019 (2019.IA.101) an additonal transcripts were received in August 2021.
Additional material was deposited in 2021 (2021.IA.17) and 2023 (2023.IA.14).</p>  
      </acqinfo>
      <processinfo id="aspace_56296cebb8b60cbf7c243c1d4c40ec4a">
         <head>Processing Information</head>
         <p>This finding aid was created by Nancy Enneking in March 2016 and updated in March and July 2017, December 2018, August 2021, and August 2023.</p>  
      </processinfo>
      <relatedmaterial id="aspace_7ee655fbe76adb227d0b0397a0efed93">
         <head>Related Materials</head>
         <p>J. Paul Getty Trust Oral History Transcripts, 1999-2010. Institutional Archives, Getty Research Institute, Finding aid no. IA10024.</p>
         <p>Interviews with Art Historians, 1991-2002.  Getty Research Institute, Accession no. 940109.</p>
         <p>Art Education History Archives Project, 1998-1999, Getty Education Institute.  Institutional Archives, Getty Research Institute, Finding aid no. IA20034.</p>  
      </relatedmaterial>
      <controlaccess>
         <subject source="lcsh">Historic sites -- Conservation and restoration</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Art objects -- Conservation and restoration</subject>
         <subject source="lcsh">Artists -- United States -- 20th century</subject>
         <corpname authfilenumber="n85199077" source="naf">Getty Conservation Institute</corpname>
         <corpname authfilenumber="n79046211" source="naf">J. Paul Getty Museum</corpname>
      </controlaccess>
      <dsc>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref20_3g2" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Interviews with the arts community, </unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">0.7 Linear Feet</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <physdesc altrender="part">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">68.6 GB</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                         datechar="creation"
                         era="ce"
                         normal="2015/2019"
                         type="inclusive">2015-2019</unitdate>
               <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest"
                    xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/10020/IA10030artscommunity"
                    xlink:show="new"
                    xlink:title="(IA10030) Getty Oral History Program: Interviews with the arts community"
                    xlink:type="simple">
                  <daodesc>
                     <p>(IA10030) Getty Oral History Program: Interviews with the arts community</p>
                  </daodesc>
               </dao>
            </did>
            <arrangement id="aspace_b6472f97b15f00fc4421590cf742e6f3">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>Interviews are in alphabetical order by the last name of the interviewee.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <bioghist id="aspace_1eab4ad22fd75a9e397606f087a04d63">
               <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
               <p>Interviews with the Arts Community includes the continuation of earlier oral history projects "Interviews Regarding the Study of Art History" and "Interviews with Art Historians".  The new category, however, has been expanded to include conservators, conservation scientists, relevant arts philanthropists, and art museum directors and curators. The purpose of this category is to capture the current state of the field within which the Getty works and provide a context for understanding the developing role of the Getty within it.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_9ba6525916f7dd6d9a75d29e451a43fb">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Records currently consist of the printed transcript and  Word, PDF, MP3 and MP4, wav, and raw video files, dating 2015-2019, of the oral histories created as a part of the new 2015- Getty Oral History Program initiated by Trust President James Cuno and conducted by Martin Meeker, oral historian with The Oral History Center, Bancroft Library, University of California Berkeley.  Interviews and video clips may be viewed under the <extref xlink:show="new"
                          xlink:actuate="onRequest"
                          xlink:href="http://www.lib.berkeley.edu/libraries/bancroft-library/oral-history-center/search-oral-histories">Getty Trust</extref> project on the Berkeley Oral History Center website.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <c02 id="aspace_d8567954e01b56d6442e12921440dee1" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Irwin, Robert with Jim Duggan: <emph render="italic">Robert Irwin's Central Garden at the Getty Museum</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2016/2016">2016</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - 2.5-inch legal "
                             id="aspace_a662433d5821fcf2a05389a9a38b46fc"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2017.IA.61-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_ea19ac63ad2d8c2f16d06e2ace3f200e">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY
(https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed 
under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_78ee11922295ee136ec838fb8d2ff16c">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Robert Irwin with Jim Duggan, "Robert Irwin's Central Garden at the Getty Museum" conducted by Martin Meeker in 2016, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2017.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9055267f0d4b7c518cc75a832f9cc823" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Lamelas, David: <emph render="italic">David Lamelas: A Pioneer in Conceptual Art</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2017/2017">2017</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_9718f8e000d7effb516666f007cdc0af"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-03</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_a5a5616c81a6100f76537a5c7b6734b8">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY
(https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_abae90695ee72244d9b4b04f4bd42f2e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ortiz-Torres, Rubén</unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2017/2017">2017</unitdate>
                  <abstract id="aspace_2b0ef531b71f56ef5d074b55876b3717">Video and sound recordings. No transcript.</abstract>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_a773b844bc16ae4feef64fa6d3aa7c8f"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2023.IA.14-01</container>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_ref3_pn0" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Ruscha, Edward: <emph render="italic">Ed Ruscha: Artist</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            datechar="creation"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="2015/2015">2015</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_0d7d19f2bb2268dd0b9851e13fba143c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2016.IA.34-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_51e0fcfffe126960bde2389d5ffebb31">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_b872cced240302fbedf2d177a7871ce4">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:  Edward Ruscha, "Ed Ruscha:  Artist" conducted by Martin Meeker, Andrew Perchuk, and James Cuno in 2015, Oral History Center of the Bancroft Library, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2016.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_289cfc207ddfaeb8dda9e19099173dd8" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Stoner, Joyce Hill: <emph render="italic">Joyce Hill Stoner: My Life in Art Conservation and Intersections with the Getty</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_9dec10f53105a395b7f69475a116c08e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_a4c567df74e26a6ef7110ade9ee7ac21">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_6e6bc3cfb53f508c4ab204035922dc68">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Joyce Hill Stoner "Joyce Hill Stoner: My Life in Art Conservation and Intersections with the Getty" conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2019, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2020.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_042672004d02a2b4d97102b292fcc28d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Terrill, Joey: <emph render="italic">Joey Terrill: At the Forefront of Queer Chicano Art</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2017/2017">2017</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_672cf0635d8877a10f6848c4ac81ffce"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2018.IA.76-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_7f7e5e38d100ffe92c51585323d1fd17">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY
(https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed 
under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_00c34fe771904a4862af2875151ad2f1">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Joey Terrill, "Joey Terrill: at the Forefront of Queer Chicano Art" conducted by Todd Holmes in 2017, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2017.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
         </c01>
         <c01 id="aspace_ref19_o2h" level="series">
            <did>
               <unittitle>Interviews of significant Getty trustees and staff, </unittitle>
               <physdesc altrender="whole">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">1.5 Linear Feet</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <physdesc altrender="part">
                  <extent altrender="materialtype spaceoccupied">154 GB</extent>
               </physdesc>
               <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                         datechar="creation"
                         era="ce"
                         normal="2016/2022"
                         type="inclusive">2016-2022</unitdate>
               <dao xlink:actuate="onRequest"
                    xlink:href="http://hdl.handle.net/10020/ia10030"
                    xlink:show="new"
                    xlink:title="(IA10030) Selected Getty Oral History Program interviews, overseen/conducted by Martin Meeker, University of California, Berkeley"
                    xlink:type="simple">
                  <daodesc>
                     <p>(IA10030) Selected Getty Oral History Program interviews, overseen/conducted by Martin Meeker, University of California, Berkeley</p>
                  </daodesc>
               </dao>
            </did>
            <scopecontent id="aspace_92f7d9007f815290f3abb6a6f9007d71">
               <head>Scope and Contents</head>
               <p>Records currently consist of the printed transcript and  Word, PDF, MP3 and MP4, wav, and raw video files, dating 2016-2022, of the oral histories created as a part of the new 2015- Getty Oral History Program initiated by Trust President James Cuno and overseen by Martin Meeker, oral historian with The Oral History Center, Bancroft Library, University of California Berkeley.  Interviews and video clips may be viewed under the <extref xlink:show="new"
                          xlink:actuate="onRequest"
                          xlink:href="http://www.lib.berkeley.edu/libraries/bancroft-library/oral-history-center/search-oral-histories">Getty Trust</extref> project on the Berkeley Oral History Center website.</p>
            </scopecontent>
            <bioghist id="aspace_94f49425bd52dcab9a7b4ffdca9b09a0">
               <head>Biographical / Historical</head>
               <p>This portion of the 2015-ongoing Getty Oral History Project continues conducting interviews with significant Getty trustees and staff, commencing with the departure of former President and CEO Barry Munitz in 2006, and using a thematic approach, e.g., "the resolution of the governance crisis in 2006-2007 (Attorney General investigation, LA Times articles, etc.)," "the negotiations with Italy and Greece over the return of antiquities," "the hiring of Jim Wood as President/CEO," "the response to the financial crisis," "Jim Wood's tenure as President/CEO," "the development of the individual Programs since 2006," and "reflections of the Trustees upon their departure," among other topics.</p>
            </bioghist>
            <arrangement id="aspace_b457f2ed1491a8795aeb44d239d3d5a8">
               <head>Arrangement</head>
               <p>Interviews are in alphabetical order by the last name of the interviewee.</p>
            </arrangement>
            <c02 id="aspace_2b42b821b905f3e96f1dd35ad8df5d70" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Agnew, Neville, Getty Conservation Institute: <emph render="italic">Neville Agnew: Thirty Years of Cultural Heritage Site Conservation with the Getty Trust</emph>,   </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            datechar="creation"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="2016-07/2016-07">July 2016</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_2e3520ccce345c37bb895bb2aa1bc1a5">(2 copies)</physdesc>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_5aa62fb28b016d6808b349532a11f3e2"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2016.IA.34-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_561c72fc504130f2174e7a77b2ebc21b">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_c872404e040128f6f2cbb4670f26f9c1">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Neville Agnew, "Neville Agnew: Thirty Years of Cultural Heritage Site Conservation with the Getty Trust" conducted by Todd Holmes in 2016, Oral History Center of the Bancroft Library, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2017.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_c67ca552b95a6f6fa82c8dcdb6ab6cc7" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Considine, Brian, J. Paul Getty Museum: <emph render="italic">Conservation and Craftsmanship: Brian Considine, Senior Conservator of Decorative Arts &amp; Architecture at the J. Paul Getty Museum</emph>,   </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            datechar="creation"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="2017/2017">2017</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_322161a8dcb26db4993be28c98a38789">(2 copies)</physdesc>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - 2.5-inch legal "
                             id="aspace_eef696ed1db33c7669517477ea7e993e"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2017.IA.61-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_fc29e476c2429d86ecdb597af683f909">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_48a8cfba5239087a6d9d1e4c2cfdce63">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>Brian Considine, "Conservation and Craftsmanship: Brian Considine, Senior Conservator of Decorative Arts and Architecture at the J. Paul Getty Museum", conducted by Cristina Kim in 2017, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2017.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_60f947d13e2e0bfaccb2c316c2d9f972" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Dardes, Kathleen: <emph render="italic"> Kathleen Dardes: My Years in Conservation, 1981-2019</emph>,</unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_cd5bfd08a34d6faec1279270b37a5038"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-03</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_b92a16861593812eb2757223412481bc">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
               </userestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_b028faa756d45a07ae34aa16ecff18e6" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Druzik, Jim, Getty Conservation Institute:  <emph render="italic">Foxes and Hedgehogs: Jim Druzik and the Development of the Field of Conservation Science</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate calendar="gregorian"
                            datechar="creation"
                            era="ce"
                            normal="2016-07/2016-07">July 2016</unitdate>
                  <physdesc id="aspace_13ed87992204bf7d6c8b72b1408c8544">(2 copies)</physdesc>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_0450bb604e096176b3f4934ea5843348"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2016.IA.34-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_73a5e84a29d009fa8480d9575957fda8">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_6cf0efe22efe2741d94dde3bf32c4748">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Jim Druzik, "Foxes and Hedgehogs: Jim Druzik and the Development of the Field of Conservation Science" conducted by Paul Burnett in 2016, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2017.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_961f8937f4f3d7e8951b61c9e9b46857" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Gaehtgens, Thomas, Getty Research Institute: <emph render="italic">Thomas Gaehtgens: Fifty Years of Scholarship and Innovation in Art History, from the Free University of Berlin to the Getty Research Institute</emph>,</unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2022">2022</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_de88565708d5db554b9d2c93d1a8e4c1"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2023.IA.14-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_aaa6a3cd3c94c516ca858975c739690e">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>All uses of this manuscript are covered by a legal agreement between The Regents of the University of California and Thomas Gaehtgens dated February 17, 2021. The manuscript is thereby made available for research purposes. All literary rights in the manuscript, including the right to publish, are reserved to The Bancroft Library of the University of California, Berkeley.</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_4930e80f6ad509cf5f06a084b69d876d">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>Thomas Gaehtgens, "Thomas Gaehtgens: Fifty Years of Scholarship and Innovation in Art History, from the Free University of Berlin to the Getty Research Institute" conducted by Todd Holmes in 2017, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, 2022.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_a828f73e68932d2da39306002585346a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hamma, Kenneth, J. Paul Getty Museum and J. Paul Getty Trust: <emph render="italic">Kenneth Hamma: Antiquities and Technology at the Getty</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_1f9a44d9d65850bb50e375c9aa89d65a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_214cf4588ae347bb56d1bfc446615e84">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_96a9b85f47b104f15ab16dc0e2e40de0">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Kenneth Hamma, "Kenneth Hamma: Antiquities and Technology at the Getty" conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2019, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2019.</p>
               </prefercite>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_bd99cc90c8035459f4944ce21232958e">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Transcript only.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_8980d82e7e01ad29489bae0c918de46d" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hartwig, Ron A, Vice President of Communications, J. Paul Getty Trust: <emph render="italic">Ron A. Hartwig: A Career in Communications</emph>  [SEALED until August 1, 2023]</unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2018/2018">2018</unitdate>
               </did>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_258fc072607e37909446d43fb01684b5">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This transcript has been sealed in its entirety by Ron Hartwig until August 1, 2023.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_43170f96cf946cb1c174b098c3b1fb35" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Hibbard, Sally:  <emph render="italic">Sally Hibbard: Forty Years of Change at the J. Paul Getty Museum</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_01f1fb615670d40c777c79c7622e013c"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-03</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_45adc0c188522eb77790f4ade223988c">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
               </userestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_a936fd1f9a1c7c841ee995b485cf75a9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Kozberg, Joanne Corday, Trustee: <emph render="italic">Joanne Corday Kozberg:  The Getty Trust from a Trustee's Perspective, 2005-2017</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2018/2018">2018</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_28285535a5cc058b6bd5f8fc883d2e2a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2018.IA.76-01</container>
               </did>
               <prefercite id="aspace_77b1606ebd398936bef6f8054f67c48c">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>Joanne Corday Kozberg, "Joanne Corday Kozberg: The Getty Trust from a Trustee's Perspective, 2005-2017" conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2018, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2018.</p>
               </prefercite>
               <userestrict id="aspace_0498dfc0d1520d5fe690fbb59702eb73">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY
(https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed 
under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_9f19a858ae59d84218cc8151dcb2cd54" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Kren, Thomas, J. Paul Getty Museum: <emph render="italic">Thomas Kren: My Thirty-Nine Years as a Curator at the Getty</emph> SEALED UNTIL 2026</unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate>
               </did>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_a01f3711f318724678cc9ea5c794fe19" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Leonard, Mark: <emph render="italic">Mark Leonard: Building New Traditions in Paintings Conservation at the Getty, 1983-2010</emph>,</unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2020/2020">2020</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_b4f05a91331364b8a1f240bda67396fe"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-03</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_cd13f28f3c7b89c17700009b88d5333a">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
               </userestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_6025e90d9b9a0272d293696a6aff5a7a" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Podany, Jerry, J. Paul Getty Museum: <emph render="italic">Jerry Podany: Four Decades of Conserving Antiquities at the Getty Museum</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2022/2022">2022</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_2550e21f87175cd8297e21cc6946a866"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2023.IA.14-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_eb4cd52845976d7483371ec5dccc2b6f">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_a1038caec04cfdcedb9f66fe4e619cdf">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This interview transcript has been substantially edited by the narrator. Audiovisual will only be available upon request, and researchers may not use it for quotes or clips where it differs too widely from the edited transcript.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_e1612dc497aec641370062f080d4d949">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>Jerry Podany, "Jerry Podany: Four Decades of Conserving Antiquities at the Getty Museum" conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2022, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, 2022, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2022.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_269b233134fd64a7814274c7373583e2" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Price, Merritt, J. Paul Getty Museum: <emph render="italic">Merritt Price: Building the Design Department at the Getty</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="202/202">2020</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_140634a386bb884fbe46bfed1989e7f5"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_c980ee35750bbd7bf0e9babe0bd77604">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_f7f7589a2d525576c6ac17271fed5f3d">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Merritt Price, "Merritt Price: Building the Design Department at the Getty" conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2020, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2021.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_149a90f2acf26b859141d3f07208705e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Schilling, Michael R, Getty Conservation Institute: <emph render="italic">Michael R. Schilling: Chemical Analysis of Art at the Getty Conservation Institute</emph> 
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_766f862917cae4a3357417d178c85b8a"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_6353d9f38014160cd0771bea67e3f382">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_9e9e552e063996285e3957e851f1f561">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Michael R. Schilling, "Michael R. Schilling: Chemical Analysis of Art at the Getty Conservation Institute" conducted by Roger Eardley-Prior in 2019, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2020.</p>
               </prefercite>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_75b4026679d9199ea65fb072147f9b31">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Transcript only.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_b2878c0a579d9a380cfefc661b5562f9" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Siart, Bill, Trustee: <emph render="italic">A Life of Service in Art and Education: Bill Siart and the Getty Board of Trustees</emph>, </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2018/2018">2018</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Legal "
                             id="aspace_a2549591e489ad7b60be4150296e19e4"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2018.IA.76-01</container>
               </did>
               <prefercite id="aspace_3dacb0fd3c380c14dec17c23fd2abdc9">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>Bill Siart "A Life of Service in Art and Education: Bill Siart and the Getty Board of Trustees" conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2018, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2018.</p>
               </prefercite>
               <userestrict id="aspace_e7e800abfe7c29a0bb5acc287fed534f">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY
(https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed 
under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_5a91336f369286170e57561cf7384c2e" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Szafran, Yvonne, J. Paul Getty Museum: <emph render="italic">Yvonne Szafran: Forty Years of Painting Conservation at the J. Paul Getty Museum</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2018/2018">2018</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - Standard Letter "
                             id="aspace_a4bca0009527ea51fb284b94e56972a0"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2021.IA.17-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_67aadfa52795d57a07b8046a271c2d32">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_a1f8e33ab3490ca8b35a4e342ce46e08">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>Yvonne Szafran, "Yvonne Szafran: Forty Years of Painting Conservation at the J. Paul Getty Museum" conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2018, Oral History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2020.</p>
               </prefercite>
               <scopecontent id="aspace_ad7b0acc9543356cb58af7c55ad7cee6">
                  <head>Scope and Contents</head>
                  <p>Transcript only.</p>
               </scopecontent>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_efe6669d7855b9de5fe8aa0665536460" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Taylor, Peter J., Trustee: <emph render="italic">Peter J. Taylor: The Getty Trust from a Trustee's Perspective, 2005-2017</emph>
                  </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2019/2019">2019</unitdate>
                  <container altrender="Hollinger - 2.5-inch legal "
                             id="aspace_7fd4eec19bb6bc3140e12ef4a0982aef"
                             label="Mixed Materials"
                             type="box">2019.IA.101-01</container>
               </did>
               <userestrict id="aspace_9fc3a546731f83eb534044cb9b65542b">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Use</head>
                  <p>Copyright in the manuscript and recording is owned by the J. Paul Getty Trust, which has made the materials available under Creative Commons licenses as follows: Manuscript is licensed under CC-BY (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/4.0/) and recording is licensed under CC-BY-NC (https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-nc/4.0/)</p>
               </userestrict>
               <prefercite id="aspace_26ef82849d2a0b073dee0c7075199728">
                  <head>Preferred Citation</head>
                  <p>It is recommended that this oral history be cited as follows:
Peter J. Taylor, "Peter J. Taylor: The Getty Trust from a Trustee's Perspective, 2005-2017," conducted by Amanda Tewes in 2018, Oral
History Center, The Bancroft Library, University of California, Berkeley, under the auspices of the J. Paul Getty Trust, 2019.</p>
               </prefercite>
            </c02>
            <c02 id="aspace_1ba4556cb3f43584817f8faaf268969f" level="file">
               <did>
                  <unittitle>Woodworth, Patricia, Vice President, Chief Operations Office, and
Chief Financial Officer, J. Paul Getty Trust: <emph render="italic"> Patricia Woodworth: Patricia Woodworth on Getty Trust Finances and Operations </emph>  [SEALED until January 1, 2029] </unittitle>
                  <unitdate datechar="creation" normal="2018/2018">2018</unitdate>
               </did>
               <accessrestrict id="aspace_b9430f7480f7025aafc50dc3eeeb6130">
                  <head>Conditions Governing Access</head>
                  <p>This interview is sealed until January 1, 2029.</p>
               </accessrestrict>
            </c02>
         </c01>
      </dsc>
   </archdesc>
</ead>
